<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Asnickij Murat</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Asnickij Murat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 01:41:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Good and the Bad of Christian Fundamentalism</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/37130973-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 01:41:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/37130973-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</guid><description>The term "Christian Fundamentalism" is often used to describe a grouping of Evangelical Christians who are particularly focused on the importance of Scripture being understood literally. When talking about the "good" and the "bad" of Christian fundamentalism, it's essential to note a few qualifiers.
The title may conjure up a range of images that may or may not be accurate. Some people automatically associate the term with bigotry, dogmatism, and even terrorism.</description></item><item><title>What Does Jesus Teach Us about God's End-Times Plan?</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/81139196-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 07:52:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/81139196-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</guid><description>Jesus explained some aspects of the end times, including His return as King and Judge. In discussing end-time events, He said in Matthew 24:36 that "of that day and hour no one knows, not even the angels of heaven, nor the Son, but only the Father" (NASB). The information given here is an overview of the end-time events mentioned by Jesus and the Bible writers.
Major End-Time Events Discussed in Scripture The Olivet Discourse (Matthew 24; Mark 13) In this passage, Jesus outlines several events leading up to His second coming, which will occur at the end of the age (Matt 24:3, NASB).</description></item><item><title>4 Keys to Building Confidence in God When Life Falls Apart</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/56348013-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 03:34:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/56348013-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</guid><description>It's not an exaggeration to say that the experience of many Christians today is one of disappointment, disillusionment and despair. The brokenness in our lives may seem to shatter our trust in God. How do we maintain our confidence in God when life falls apart? Let me offer four keys.
1. Recognize God’s omnipresence The first key to maintaining confidence in God through tumultuous times is recognizing the omnipresence of God.</description></item><item><title>Self-Care: Selfish Habit or Holy Endeavor?</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/86848474-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 10:36:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/86848474-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</guid><description>“I need a break.” Has this ever been a thought in your mind? Are you feeling guilt about needing time for yourself, or are you comfortable with the idea of self care? How do we look at it as a spiritual practice rather than an indulgent luxury?
For many people, the word ‘self-care’ conjures up visions of expensive spa days and mani-pedis. It can also evoke images of people withdrawing from life or shirking their responsibilities and choosing instead to prioritize personal comfort.</description></item><item><title>Why Are There So Many Ideas about Heaven That Are Not Biblical?</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/25091432-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 16:31:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/25091432-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</guid><description>Many ideas about heaven are not biblical, or, at least, do not come primarily from the Bible. However, people's understanding of heaven can be influenced by various aspects of culture, religion, and personal experience. The beliefs people hold may not accurately represent biblical teachings. To understand this issue better, it is essential to consider the factors that contribute to these misconceptions.
Factors Behind Misconceptions about Heaven Cultural Influences Culture deeply affects an individual's worldviews and, often, colors their perception of heaven.</description></item><item><title>How Should Christians Approach Progress in Technology?</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/43153963-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 14:07:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/43153963-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</guid><description>In today’s world, technology continues to play a prominent role. The way we communicate, the way we do business and even the way we worship have all been transformed by new advancements in tech. As a Christian, it can be a challenge to navigate through this digital age and approach these innovations with wisdom and biblical discernment.
At the core of discerning technology from a Christian perspective, there are a few key principles to consider.</description></item><item><title>9 Lessons for New Christians ... And Old Ones</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/90982699-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 18:17:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/90982699-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</guid><description>New believers have a lot to learn about God, themselves and the world. But older Christians, though they've grown in their faith, still have much room for growth as well. Here are nine lessons that will help both types of followers of Christ.
1. Our main purpose is to love God and love others. When Jesus was asked about the greatest commandment, He replied by combining Deuteronomy 6:5 and Leviticus 19:18: "</description></item><item><title>One Key Reason Why Church Consultations Fail</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/50514280-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 20:43:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/50514280-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</guid><description>The vast majority of churches that engage in a consultation with an outside consultant do so because they’re hoping for positive change. Many are struggling, and they're looking to an expert to bring a fresh perspective as they navigate that struggle. However, when the process doesn't yield the desired results, it might leave some shaking their heads in puzzlement or disillusionment with the consultation process itself.
I have been honored to journey with a number of churches over the years, serving in both interim pastor and consulting roles.</description></item><item><title>Why the Church Should Take Responsibility for Its Liberties and Freedoms</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/62269773-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 07:14:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/62269773-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</guid><description>The Church as an institution, in general, has not had a great history with respect to political power or the subjugation of religious liberties to political agenda. This is not a critique of every individual that has ever been a part of the Church, but of the institutional overreach at times. To redress the balance, I believe the Church should take responsibility for its rights and freedoms and place a higher priority on actively promoting them.</description></item><item><title>Why Do Christians Emphasize Hell Instead of Not Being with God in Heaven?</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/25448119-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 12:46:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/25448119-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</guid><description>The Christian belief in the existence of heaven and hell is often a source of confusion and misunderstanding. One common critique leveled at Christianity by non-believers and some theologians is that the church emphasizes hell over the concept of not being in the presence of God in heaven. The crux of this debate is understanding why God's loving nature would include an eternal torment instead of simply excluding unbelievers from heaven.</description></item><item><title>Why Pastors Struggle to Ask for Help (And How to Get Past It)</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/91611942-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 23:20:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/91611942-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</guid><description>Ministry can be a tough job, and pastors are some of the most selfless, dedicated individuals to serve in these roles. However, given the weighty nature of their responsibilities, pastors can often feel overwhelmed, uncertain or in need of counsel from their peers. Still, many find it difficult to ask for help—whether it’s due to pride, fear, or a perception that reaching out would be inappropriate.
It’s crucial for pastors to get past this barrier in order to grow as leaders and best support their congregations.</description></item><item><title>Why Christians Can Be Bad at Being Kind</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/10891934-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 19:35:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/10891934-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</guid><description>It's quite common for people to perceive Christians as being kind and gentle individuals who go through life with hearts full of love and compassion. While there are many Godly people who genuinely manifest a selfless spirit, it's also important to acknowledge that not all Christians are who society expects them to be. The world often misinterprets the human tendency of a believer to fail just like everybody else when it comes to expressing kindness.</description></item><item><title>How to Actually Treat Other Believers Like Family</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/29322555-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 22:54:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/29322555-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</guid><description>For some time now, I’ve been hearing a common sentiment expressed by Christians and even church leaders concerning the need to overcome the poor relational state among many Christians. People are tired of feeling more like distant cousins or disconnected coworkers than actual brothers and sisters in Christ. Many are searching for more authentic community among believers. At the same time, it becomes apparent that the existing institutions—church buildings and pastoral leadership—are not serving as wellsprings of such connection as they once may have.</description></item><item><title>Why People Are Losing Their Religion (and How the Church Can Respond)</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/41681183-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 09:43:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/41681183-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</guid><description>In recent decades, there has been a significant shift in the religious landscape of Western societies. More and more people are disaffiliating from their religious backgrounds, leading to a larger “nones” population. For Christians this is a source of concern, as fewer people affiliate with Christian religion, and church attendance has stagnated or even decreased in many Western countries. However, examining the trend of religious disaffiliation offers an opportunity to better understand what has gone wrong and how we can respond to restore a vital spiritual life among our society.</description></item><item><title>Guilt and the Great Deception in the Christian Life</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/44350367-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:30:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/44350367-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</guid><description>“Guilt.” It is not a pretty word. We often avoid it or cover it up in any way possible. However, since guilt is an intricate part of the human experience – a critical part of our existence as both broken and forgiven people – we would be remiss to ignore it. Guilt is a complex phenomenon that requires us to dig beneath the surface to understand how it influences our lives, particularly as believers in Jesus Christ.</description></item><item><title>Is it My Responsibility to Help the Widows and Orphans?</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/46379584-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 13:32:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/46379584-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</guid><description>You may have heard or even asked this question: "Is it my responsibility to help the widows and orphans?" The notion of individual responsibility to help others in distress can be a tricky subject, especially when scriptural commands get intertwined with cultural concepts of charity. Let's examine the issues step by step.
Biblical Teachings on Helping Widows and Orphans In the Bible, there are multiple commands and illustrations that involve caring for the vulnerable populations of widows and orphans.</description></item><item><title>Why Should Christians Evaluate What Their Lives Are Built On?</title><link>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/23890345-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:05:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://asnickijmurat.github.io/posts/23890345-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</guid><description>A sturdy foundation is a metaphor that represents the solid framework for our lives, particularly from a Christian perspective. As believers, we must recoginze the consequences of putting our trust in shaky ground. Ecclesiastes 12:6 warns, "or ever the silver cord be loosed, or the golden bowl be broken, or the pitcher be shattered at the spring, or the wheel broken at the well, then shall both sons and daughters be companions, ready to entertain one another.</description></item></channel></rss>